Fady Faheem

Fort Worth, TX (682) 717-6391

<u>contact@fadyfaheem.com</u> - E-Portfolio: fadyfaheem.com

Languages: English & Arabic

A creative and problem-solving **software developer** with over 4+ years of delivering high-end software and frontend engineering services to high-value clients. Strong passion for both developing applications and websites with great user experiences. Currently working on difficult programming problems and learning from real-world challenges.

My skills include the following:

- HTML, CSS
- React.JS
- Swift
- C# and Unity

- Java and JavaScript
- Python
- Team Building / Leadership
- Verbal/Written Communications
- Agile/Scrum Management
- Quick Learner
- Drives Results
- Team Player

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

Software Developer – Full Time

July 2024 – Present

- Designed and implemented Flask Python APIs to integrate data ingestion for Bell Aircraft systems (Collins, Garmin, and etc...)
- Worked with multiple front-end frameworks building UI in React.JS, Svelte, Maui, and or Angular.
- Created and designed Unity applications to help streamline processes, such as XML courseware editing, and building Crew alerting system (CAS) in Unity game engine.
- 3D modelled and printed custom parts to support training in both mechanical and in-flight applications.
- Maintained over 150+ machines for classroom usage, including building a synchronization tool in C# to keep all instructor machines with up-to-date courseware.
- Developed and maintained positive relationships and contracts with internal and external customers and industry leaders.

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

Junior Software Developer – Full Time

July 2023 – July 2024

- Began development of pilot scheduling applications both on web and native mobile platforms.
- Wrote Excel VBA (Visual Basic for Applications) to forecast revenue, generate reports, and streamline administrative duties.
- Established a system to monitor, control, and maintain tools within the company, lowering tool loss by 4%
- Monitored and updated Kubernetes deployments for excessive complexity, and workflow operation, and uptime.

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

Software Developer Co-Op – Full Time

May 2023 – July 2023

- Created schematics for pilot scheduling application, tool control, and regulatory tracking application
- Learned VBA (Visual Basic for Applications) to maintain old excel macros, due to code deprecation and software updates
- Learned React.JS to begin web application development

Bell Textron Inc. Arlington, TX

IT Software Intern – Part-Time

Sep 2022 – May 2023

 Created and designed a 2-year plan to efficiently develop software solutions, including streamlining digital access, creating alternative solutions for data digestion, and more Edikt Studios Keller, TX

Intern Unity Game Developer – Full Time

Aug 2021 – May 2023

- Developed 2D and 3D games utilizing HDRP (High Definition Render Pipeline), and URP (Universal Render Pipeline) to maximize user visual interaction
- Created AR/VR Games including "Math Hunt" that went on to go to being a finalist in SkillsUSA Texas
- Leveraged advanced tools and techniques to create immersive and interactive experiences that push the boundaries of traditional gaming

Gourmet Wholesale LLC Colleyville, TX

Assistant Technical Manager - Full Time

Oct 2020 - Nov 2021

- Maintained a MySQL database for efficient inventory management.
- Developed a web application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to streamline inventory maintenance and offer an online platform for clients to view available items.
- Implemented a tracking map that reduced item misplacement losses by 32%, enhancing inventory accuracy and operational efficiency.

EDUCATION

University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, TX

Undergraduate in Computer Science Engineering